어 로스 이런 걸 보게 될 줄은
상상도 못했겠지만..
Oh, okay ,Ross, I , I realize that you didn't expect to walk in
and see that but let me explain ok?
내가 설명할게
우리 아무 것도 안하고 있었어!
We weren't doing anything!
Rach, he just saw us.
레이첼, 방금 다 보고있었다고.
Shhh.
쉬잇~!
방금 니가 본 게 다야 키스 한번!
But what you saw that, that is the extent of it, okay? One kiss.
No, come on, that is a lie, we also kissed in Barbados.
아냐 거짓말이야
우리 발베이도스에서도 키스했어.
Dude, chill!
가만히 좀 있어봐!
Oh, okay. We also kissed in Barbados but
좋아, 우리 바베이도스에서도 키스했어.
하지만 그건 니가 찰리랑
키스하는 걸 보고 나서 그런 거야.
we didn't plan it, okay?
And the only reason that happened was, was
because I saw you kissing Charlie.
그래 이거 다 니가 시작한 거라고!
Yeah! You started it!
I have got to chill!
나 좀 말려줘!
물론 이러기 전에
너랑 먼저 얘기를 했어야하는 건데..
Look, we, we probably should've talked to you about this before it ever happened but ...
Ah, we feel so terrible about this Ross.
정말 미안해.
Yeah, but it did happen. So...
하지만 이렇게 되버렸네.
Ross?
로스?
그냥 문 닫아버릴까?
Can we just close the door?
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
Friends 10x02 TOWhere Ross is fine
Transcribed by Kevin Kim (vneumann@korea.com)
1002 The One Where Ross Is Fine
So no one told you that was gonna be this way
[ 제 작 ]
코리아닷컴 프렌즈동호회 자막팀
Your job's a joke, you're broke.
Your love life's DOA.
자막팀의 동의 없이 수정/배포는 금합니다
It's like you're always stuck in 2nd gear.
자막에 대한 피드백은
동호회 게시판으로 해주십시요
But when it hasn't been your day, your week,
http://club.korea.com/friends
your month, or even your year but...
I'll be there for you.
'Cause you were there for me too~
Ross, say something.
로스, 아무 말이나 해봐. 아무 말이나..
Anything.
So you two are ...
그러니까 늬들 둘이 서로..
Yeah.
응..
그럼 둘이 그건...
And have you had ...?
No. No. no.no.no.
아니, 아니.
But if I hadn't walked in here, would you ...?
만약 내가 지금 안 들어왔다면 아마..
아마도.. 아니, 아니.
Probably...No! No!
Ross, this is not how we wanted you to find out about this.
너한테 이런 식으로 알리려던 건 절대 아냐.
화를 내도 우린 할말 없어.
You have every right to go nuts.
I'm not going nuts.
나 화 안났는데?
지금 내가 화나보여?
Do you see me going nuts?
아니 그건 아니지만..
무슨 말인지 알잖아.
No, but you know what I mean?
Hey, hey, hey, ....
이봐 이봐 이봐.
If you two are happy, then I'm happy for you.
늬들 둘이 행복하다면 난 축하해줄 일이지.
난 멀쩡해!
I'm Fine!
진짜?
Really?
당연하지~
멀쩡하대두?
Absolutely! I'm fine!
Totally fine!
너무 멀쩡해.
왜 목소리가 이리 째져서 나오는진 몰라도
I..I don't know why it's going out aloud and squeaky
cause really I'm fine!
나 멀.쩡.해.
I'm not saying I wasn't a little surprised
물론 둘이 키스하는 걸 보고
한 개도 안 놀랐다는 말은 아니지.
to watch you guys kissing I mean at first I was like ...
처음엔 아~~ 이랬지만
지금은.. 다 정리가 됐고
But now that I've had time to absorb it,
아주 맘에 들어.
loving this.
로스.
Ross,...
이제 다 말이 되는 거 같애.
It's all working out.
나랑 찰리, 그리고 너희 둘.
Me and Charlie, and you two.
You know what we should do?
나한테 좋은 생각이 있어!
Calm ourselves?
마음 진정시키기?
No, we should all have dinner.
아니~~
우리 넷이 같이 식사하는 거야.
내일 저녁 좋다. 내가 요리할게!
Yes, we'll do it tomorrow night. I'll cook!
아.. 그거 좀 이상하지 않을까?
Look, don't, don't you think that'll be a little weird?
이상해? 뭐가? 아무 문제 없어.
Weird? Why? What's weird?
매운 음식을 못먹는 사람은 참을 수 없겠지
나 화히타 만들 거거든!
The only thing weird would be someone didn't like Mexican food because I'm making FAJITAs!
I do like fajitas.
난 화히타 문제없는데.
God, this adoption stuff is so overwhelming.
이 입양문제 아주 골치 아픈데?
종류도 너무 많아.
There's intercountry adoption, dependency adoption,
so many ways to go and this is like the biggest decision of our lives.
우리 인생에서 너무나도
중요한 기로에 서있는 거라고.
There's a hair in my coffee.
내 커피에 머리카락 떠다녀.
안녕 얘들아.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
안녕.
Hey, have you seen Frank Jr.?
얘들아 혹시 내 동생 봤어?
세쌍둥이 데리고 여기서 만나기로 했는데.
Cause he's meeting me here with the triplets.
You know, it's funny.
웃기지, 니가 '세쌍둥이'라는 말을 할 때마다
3명의 섹시한 금발의 19세 소녀들이 떠올라.
Everytime you say triplets I immediately think of three, hot, blonde 19 year olds.
That's sweet.
깜찍해라~
니 머리카락이나 마셔.
Drink your hair.
이건 다 뭐야?
Hey, what's all this stuff?
Ah, they're brochures from different adoption agencies.
입양 기관에서 받아온 팜플렛들.
Woo, babies!
어머 애기들~
Oh, this one is so cute. Get this one.
야 얘 진짜 귀엽다, 얘로 해.
That's not really how it works.
그런 식으로 고르는 게 아니야.
-Oh, how does it work?
-I don't know!
-그럼 어떻게 하는데?
-나도 몰라!
Well, if you're having a hard time, you should talk to my friends , Bill and Coleen.
결정하기 힘들면
내 친구 빌하고 콜린한테 물어봐.
걔네도 입양했거든. 분명 도와줄거야.
They adopted a kid. I'm sure they'd help you.
Thanks! That would be great.
아 그거 정말 좋겠다. 고마워.
Hey Honey, wouldn't that be great?
자기야 잘됐지?
Alright, alright, alright, remember what we talked about.
자 자 우리 얘기한 거 기억하지?
공공장소에서는 지켜야 할 약속들이 있는 거야.
When we're in a public place, there're certain rules.
That's not what we talked about!
그게 아니잖아!
Hey, Frank. / Hi.
안녕.
정말 오랜만이다.
Good to see you.
Good to see you, too.
누나두 정말 오랜만이다.
안녕, 잘지냈지?
Hi, how are you doing?
Oh my goodness! They've all gotten so big!
잘 왔어. 어쩜, 애들 정말 많이 컸네.
Which one is which again?
누가 누구지?
Oh, well, ah...
아,
저기 여자 가방에서 생리대 꺼내 노는 애가
프랭크 주니어 주니어고,
That's uh Frank Jr. Jr. pulling the tampons out of that lady's purse.
And uh ...
그리고, 어...
That's uh Chandler climbing on Chandler.
저기 챈들러 뒤에서 노는 애가.. 챈들러고,
And uh...
어, 또, 어...
That's Leslie throwing bagels at him.
그리고 저기 베이글 뜯어던지는 애가 레슬리.
세쌍둥이를 입양하시겠습니까?
아뇨!
Willing to adopt triplets?........ No!
Ah, Can I just say I know we're doing this for Ross and that's cool but...
로스를 위해서 하는 거니까 어쩔 수 없지만,
만약 이럴 필요 없었다면
우리 첫 데이트가 이렇진 않았을 거야.
if it was up to me, this is not what we'd be doing on our first date.
Well, what would we be doing?
그럼 대신 뭘 했을까?
I'd take you out for a romantic night.
물론 아주 로맨틱한 저녁을 만들어주겠지.
Some champagne, fancy dinner,
샴페인 마시면서
근사하게 저녁 식사도 하고..
feel you up on a carriage ride home...
마차 타고 집에 돌아오는 길에
너랑 그런짓도 하고..
Feel me up?
그런짓?
In the carriage!
마차에서잖아~
Hey,Charlie. / Hi
찰리~ / 안녕.
안녕.
Hi Hey.
So ...
그래...
dreading this? / Oh, you bet.
-걱정되죠?
-물론이죠!
I saw it. Did you bring a little something for Ross?
로스 줄 거 갖고 온 거야?
Actually, uh, it's some stuff you left at my apartments.
아니 실은 니가 내 집에
놔두고 간 물건들이야.
Oh. oh. Thanks.
어, 어 그래 고마워.
And you know, you can just give me my stuff whenever you want.
아 그리고 내 물건들은..
아무 때나 돌려줘.
Yeah, I didn't throw any of that out.
그래, 그거 하나도 안 버렸어.
Oh, I thought I heard voices!
목소리가 들리는 거 같았다니까!
Hi Charlie!
찰리 안녕~
어이 조이~
Hey, Joey!
And uh oh you're gonna have to introduce me to your new girlfriend. Huh?
오 그리고 니 새 여자친구한테
소개 좀 시켜줘야겠는데?
I was kidding. I know Rachel. I know.
그냥 장난이야 장난.
레이첼인 거 다 안다고. 알고 있어.
Come. Please come in, come in.
들어와, 들어와.
Okay, ah, well , we brought you some wine.
와인 가져왔어.
Oh! That is so thoughtful.
오우 고마워라.
She's a keeper.
사려도 깊다니깐~
What did you bring me, huh?
넌 뭐 갖고 온 거야?
어 그건..
Actually that's uh...
Underwear, toothbrush, and uh Van Halen CD.
속옷이랑 칫솔,
Van Halen 씨디까지.
I can use all these things!
다 쓸만한 것들이네~
Gosh, you know, Ross. You seem a little ...
어 로스, 있지 지금 상태가 좀..
What? Fine?
아주 좋아보인다고?
Because I am!
왜냐면 아주 좋거든.
Huh? Aren't you?
넌 안 그래? 너흰 안 그래?
Who, who else is fine?
또 상태 아주 좋은 사람?
Okay, listen, hey, Ross, why don't you , uh try to relax, okay?
로스. 잠깐 진정해봐.
술이라도 한잔 할까?
Maybe have a drink.
You know what? That is a very good idea!
그거 아주 좋은 생각이야.
I'm gonna go make a pitcher of margaritas.
내가 당장 가서
마가리타 피처 하나 만들어올게.
저거 봐. 너무 귀엽다.
Oh, God. So adorable.
Look at them sleeping. They're like angels.
마치 잠든 천사들 같아.
Yeah, I really cherish these moments cause ,
응 이런 순간들이 정말 너무 소중해.
곧 있으면 또 깨서 날뛸 테니까..
before you know it, they're gonna be awake again.
Well, they may be a handful but they're so cute. / Yeah.
-좀 피곤하긴 하겠지만 너무 귀엽잖아.
-그렇지.
Oh, God Last time I baby-sat them, they did the funniest thing.
아 맞다. 내가 전에 애들 돌볼 때
정말 웃긴 일 있었어.
I haven't slept in 4 years!
나 4년째 잠을 못자고 있어.
It's, It's a long time.
그거 아주 긴 기간인걸.
얼마나 힘든 일인지 누난 몰라.
You just don't know how hard it is , Phoebe.
There're just so many of them.
셋은 너무 많다고.
You know, two I can handle.
둘, 그래 둘은 내가 감당할 수 있겠어.
Two's great. You just hold one on each hand.
그냥 양팔에 하나씩 안으면 되잖아.
But what do I do when the third one
runs at me with this bike helmet on.
하지만 만약에 세번째 아이가 자전거 헬멧을 쓰고
나한테 돌진해오면 어떡하라고.
I've got no more hands to protect my area!
'거기' 방어할 손이 없잖아!
There's 3 of them, Phoebe. Three.
셋이야 누나. 셋!
응 잘 알고있어.
애들이 내 '거기'에서 나올 때 다 세봤다고.
Yeah, I know Frank. I counted them
when they were coming out of my area.
어떤 땐 말야, 나 아주 그냥..
Sometimes I think that I ...
Oh, no, no, I can't say. It's too horrible. No.
아 안돼, 안돼.
너무 끔찍한 생각이야.
What?
뭔데?
No, no, I can't.
안돼 말못해
세상에나,
너 지금 도망갈 생각 하는거야?
Oh my God , Frank. Are you thinking of leaving ?
Because I didn't have those triplets so you could just run out on them.
너 도망가라고 내가
세쌍둥이를 가진 게 아니었다고.
아니, 아냐. 절대 그러지 않아.
Oh, no! I would never do that! No!
내 말은.. 그냥 혹시...
I was just thinking that, you know...,
maybe you could take one.
누나가 하나 맡아줄 수 없나 하는 거지.
What?
뭐?
애들을 갈라놓겠다고? 말도 안돼!
You can't separate them. That's terrible!
Which one?
셋 중 누구?
Thank you so much for seeing us.
시간 내주셔서 고마워요.
Phoebe has told us such great things about you guys.
피비한테 말 많이 들었어요.
도움이 될 수 있어서 다행이죠.
Ugh, please. We're happy to help.
저희도 입양할 때 똑같이 힘들었으니까요.
We went through the same thing when we were adopting.
So what a malfunctioning wee-wees and hoo-hoos in this room, huh?
제 기능 못하는 사람들의 모임 같군요.
I mean you have a lovely home.
제 말은, 집이 아주 멋지네요.
Well, we appreciate anything you can tell us.
아무 말이나 해주시면 감사하겠어요.
Well, actually, I think this might help.
아마 이게 도움이 될 것 같네요.
It's pretty much, all the information you need.
필요한 모든 정보가 다 있을 거에요.
Oh my God!
맙소사.
Everything is broken down into categories and then cross-referenced.
모든 내용을 분류해서
전후 참조가 가능하고
색깔별로 구분해놨어요.
And then color-coded to correspond to the forms in the back.
Thank you.
고마워요.
I think I just had a tiny orgasm.
방금 쬐끄만 오르가즘을 느낀 거 같애.
You know the process is frustrating but ...
과정이 좀 복잡하지만
충분한 가치가 있는 일이에요.
It's so worth it.
Adopting Owen was the best thing that ever happened to us.
오웬을 입양한 건
정말 우리에겐 최고의 행운이었어요.
That's great.
정말 잘됐네요.
Can I see the book?
책 좀 봐도 될까?
You want me to wash my hands first, don't you?
손이라도 닦고 올까?
그냥.. 너무 이쁘게 잘 만들었잖아.
It's, it's just so pretty and white.
화장실은 거실 끝 왼쪽에 있어요.
Bathroom is down the hall, to your left.
I would have told him to do it, too.
저였어도 그렇게 시켰을 거에요.
Can I adopt you?
당신을 입양할 순 없을까요?
Hey, you must be Owen. / Yeah.
-아 니가 오웬이구나.
-예.
I'm Chandler.
난 챈들러라고 해.
Hey, I was in the scouts too. / You were?
-나도 보이스카웃이었는데.
-그래요?
물론이지.
사실 우리 아버지가 거기 여성 지도자셨어.
Yeah, in fact my father was a den mother.
Huh?
에?
You know how to use a compass?
나침반 어떻게 보는지 알아?
그걸로 훈장도 받았어요.
I have a badge in it.
그래? 우와 대단한걸?
You do? That's fantastic!
보실래요?
You want to see it?
I'd love to but I've got to get back to talk to your parents.
그러고싶지만 이제 다시 너희 부모님한테 가서
어떻게 너를 입양하셨는지 마저 들어야 돼.
They're telling us all about how they adopted you.
예?
What?
뭐라고?
저 입양된 거에요?
I'm adopted?
내가 입양한거 아니다!
I've got nothing!
첫 피처는 맛이 별로였는데
You know that first batch of margaritas is not so great
but this second batch is gooood!
이번 두번째는 좀 낫네~
Well, maybe the next batch we could all get some.
다음 피처는 우리도 좀 줄래?
Oh, yeah, well this is fun, isn't it?
응, 그래.
아 이거 너무 재밌지 않아?
You know, just the four of us, just hanging.
우리 넷이 같이 어울리는 거..
야 너 괜찮아?
화히타는 언제 나오는 거야?
Dude, are you okay? and when are the fajitas gonna be ready?
나 멀쩡해. 최상이야.
난 그냥 우리가 너무 자랑스럽다고.
I'm fine! Okay? I'm great . I'm just, I'm just proud of us. You know?
이상하지도 않고 긴장감도 없고..
There's no weirdness, no tension.
No awareness.
의식도 없고..
Yeah, we make a great foursome.
우리 넷이 너무 잘 어울리는 거 같애.
We should do more stuff together.
넷이 또 뭐할까?
Whooo! Let's take a trip!
아, 그래! 여행가자!
Okay? Where do you think , we , we can go?
어때, 어때?
My fajitas!
화이타다!
Look, Charlie,
있잖아요, 찰리.
I just want you to know Ross is just having a little trouble
로스가 지금 우리 둘이 사귄다는 걸
받아들이는 게 좀 힘든 것 같아요.
adjusting to the thought of Joey and me.
You know he normally doesn't drink like this.
이렇게 마시는 걸 본 적이 없는데.
Oh, you know what? This is nothing.
이건 별 거 아니에요.
My father is a raing alcoholic.
제 아버지는 지독한 알코올중독자거든요.
죄송해요. 제가 여기 분위기를 망쳤나요?
Oh, I'm sorry. Have I made this evening uncomfortable?
Fajitas! Be careful, very hot plate! Very hot!
화히타 대령이요. 조심하세요.
접시가 아주 뜨겁거든요! 무지무지 뜨거워요!
Ross, you don't even have oven mitts on!
로스 너 지금 오븐장갑도 안 꼈잖아!
That is gonna hurt tomorrow.
내일 술 깨면 좀 아프겠네~
Okay, this is crazy.
이건 말도 안돼.
내가 니 아이들 중 하나를 맡는다는 건 말도 안되잖아.
You can't seriously be talking about me taking one of your kids, can we?
그건 그래. / 말도 안돼.
Oh, No. Of course we're not. /It's insane.
나두 알어.
I know!
Alice would never go for it, right?
앨리스가 절대 찬성 안할걸.
I don't know. She's pretty tired, too.
I think we can get her on board.
앨리스도 무지 피곤해.
아마 설득시킬 수 있을걸?
Oh, just , you know, for argument's sake, you know, hypothetically,
좋아, 그렇다면 만약에 말이지.
그냥 가정을 해보자면,
which one would you be willing to give up?
셋 중 누구를 맡기겠다는 거야?
Huh?
글쎄..
프랭크 주니어주니어?
Frank Jr. Jr?
그럼 누나한텐 최고의 선택이지.
You will be getting a really good one.
I mean you know he's really funny.
왜냐면, 걘 정말 웃기거든.
Like the other day he made up this joke,
전에 이런 농담을 했어.
What's green and says "hey, I'm a frog."?
녹색이면서 '나 개구리다' 하는 게 뭐게?
Talking frog!
말하는 개구리!
Oh no, you can't have him. He's so funny.
프랭크 주니어주니어는 안돼. 너무 재밌잖아.
어 그래 좋아. 그럼 레슬리는?
Well, alright, that's fine. What about Leslie?
Oh, no, no, not Leslie, no.
레슬리도 안돼.
She's, she's the only one that knows how to burp the alphabet.
걔만 유일하게 알파벳 트림이 가능하거든.
Alright, so that leaves Chandler.
좋아 그럼 챈들러 밖에 없네.
안돼 안돼.
Oh, no,no, you can't have Chandler. No, no, no.
She's my little genius. I've got big hopes for her.
챈들러는 내 꼬마천재소녀란 말야.
아주 기대가 크다고.
She's gonna be a doctor or ...realtor.
의사나 부동산업자가 될거야.
Wow, Frank. I think we just ran out of kids.
흠 프랭크.
이제 더 이상 선택할 아이가 없는데?
Oh, I think you're right.
어 그렇네.
Oh, Wow! Phoebe, I don't think I can give one of them up.
있잖아 누나,
나 아무도 포기 못할 것 같아.
I mean , you know, they drive me crazy but they're my babies.
날 아무리 힘들게 해도 내 자식들이잖아.
I'm sorry, Frank. I didn't realize things were so bad.
미안해 프랭크.
그렇게 힘든 줄 몰랐어.
You know? I'll, I'll help out more.
내가 더 많이 도울게.
I can, I can babysit anytime you want.
니가 말만 하면
You name the day, and I'll be there.
아무 때나 내가 애들 돌봐줄게.
How about tomorrow?
내일 어때?
Well, that's not good.
내일은 안되는데.
But you know I can move some stuff around and I'll be there.
아니 뭐 어떻게서든 해서 시간을 낼게.
You and Alice just take the whole day together.
너랑 앨리스랑 하루종일
둘이서만 시간을 보내.
정말이야?
Will you do that for us?
Are you kidding? That's what sisters are for.
당연하지.
누나 좋다는 게 뭐야?
Oh, look at them.
쟤들 좀 봐봐.
너무너무 사랑스러워.
Oh, I love you so much.
Oh, crap! Don't wake up, don't wake up!
젠장, 깨지마 깨지마!
Where are Bill and Coleen?
빌하고 콜린 어딨어?
They are in the kitchen getting us something to eat.
부엌에 있어.
우리 먹을 것 좀 내온대.
둘 다 너무 착하지 않아?
Can you believe how nice they are?
우리 당장 가야돼!
We have to leave!
Why? What did you do in the bathroom?
왜? 너 화장실에서 뭘 한거야?
화장실까지 가지도 않았어.
I didn't get to the bathroom.
I bumped into Owen on the way and he didn't know he was adopted.
중간에 오웬 만났는데
걘 입양된 사실 모르더라고.
And there's a slight chance I may have told him.
그런데 아마도
내가 그걸 말해줘버린 거 같애.
Oh my God! Where's my purse?
이런, 내 가방 어딨지?
No, you know, I can replace everything in there
아냐 그거보다 저 폴더나 챙겨. 가자!
Get that binder and let's go!
Hi!
Some little snacks for everybody.
간단한 것들 좀 준비했어요.
Oh, you don't have to eat the sour worms, those are for Owen.
꿈틀이는 안 먹어도 되요.
그건 오웬 꺼니까.
I'll go get him in a second.
제가 가서 불러올게요.
By the way, you should know, we haven't told him he's adopted yet.
아 그리고 저희가 아직 오웬한테
입양됐다는 사실을 안 알려줬거든요..
Well, kids are so intuitive.
요즘 애들이 눈치가 장난이 아니죠.
Don't you think on some level he already knows?
지금쯤이면 눈치채지 않았을까요?
I'm adopted?
저 입양됐어요?
See? Intuitive!
보셨죠? 눈치!
What? Where did you hear that?
뭐라고? 어디서 그런 말을 들었니?
이 사람이 그랬어요.
He told me!
And he paid me 50 dollars not to tell.
그리고 말하지 말라고 50불을 줬어요.
Which technically now you should give back.
약속을 안 지켰으니까 돌려줘야 돼!
You told him he's adopted?
오웬이 입양됐다고 말했어요?
I'm so sorry but you should have a sign out there or something. At least ...
정말 죄송해요. 하지만 당신들도
무슨 싸인을 내걸거나 했어야죠.
아니면 들어오는 사람들한테
귀띔을 해주거나.
whisper it to people when they come in the door.
"Owen doesn't know he's adopted and he also thinks Santa is real!"
'오웬은 입양된 거 몰라요
그리고 싼타클로스가 가짜인 것도 몰라요.'
싼타가 가짜에요?
He isn't?!
자기야 우리 빨리 가자!
We have to get out of here, baby!
여러분 우리 레이첼과 조이를 위해 건배합시다.
Everyone, I would like to make a toast...
to Rachel and Joey.
Oy.
그리고, 사랑을 위하여!
And... to love.
Ah, love.
아~ 사랑. 사-아-라-앙, 사랑!
L-O-V-E, love.
'사'는 사랑 없는 삶.
사랑 없는 삶이란 과연 무엇일까?
L is for life and what is life without love?
Oh my God, are we supposed to answer?
대답해야 되는 거야?
O, is for...
'아'는 '아오와우~!'
Oh, wow!
'라'는 라아~주 아주 놀라운 상황의 전개!
The V is for this very surprising turn of events,
which I am still fine with by the way.
하지만 난 아직도 아주 멀쩡하다고.
'앙'! 너희가 사귀는 거 난 아무런
'앙'금 없이 아주 정상적으로 받아들일 수 있어.
E!
is for how extremely normal I find it that you two ...
are together.
And now one day, you might get married
그리고 언젠가 너희 둘이 결혼도 할 수 있겠지.
and have children of your own.
애도 갖고..
Dude, are you okay?
괜찮아?
Totally.
당근!
Ross, you don't seem okay.
별로 안 괜찮아보여.
I'm sorry. It must be the pressure of entertaining.
미안, 너희를 즐겁게 해주려다보니.
I think everyone will feel better if we had some flan.
푸딩을 먹고 나면 괜찮아질 거야!
Wait, Ross. Ross, I, um I, I have to take off.
로스, 잠깐만. 나 가야 돼.
No!
안돼~
I'm sorry I have a really early class in the morning.
미안해, 하지만 내일 아침부터 강의가 있어.
But this has been lovely.
오늘밤 정말 좋았어.
Wasn't it?
그렇지?
넌 조이랑 같이 있는 게 이상할 줄 알았지?
And, and you thought it would be awkward with Joey and that
you never really liked Rachel.
레이첼도 별로 맘에 안들어했잖아.
You are on fire!
아주 필 받았구나?
아침에 전화할게, 알았지?
I'll call you in the morning, okay?
알았어.
Okay. / Alright.
God, Rachel. What Ross just said is just ....
레이첼, 방금 로스가 한 말 있잖아요..
아 괜찮아요. 나 원래 여자애들한테 인기 없어요.
Oh, that's okay. Girls tend not to like me.
알았어요.
이렇게 되면 그냥 '우리 셋이 푸딩~'
흠 운율이 맞는데?
Okay, I guess it's just flan for three.
Hey, hey, that rhymes.
있잖아, 로스. 우리도 이만 가볼게.
You know what, Ross? I think uh, I think we're gonna take off too.
Oh, oh, of course. God, I'm so stupid.
아 그래 맞아. 아 나 참 바보다.
You guys are a couple now.
너흰 이제 커플이니까
둘만의 시간을 갖고싶겠지.
I mean you probably just want to be alone.
No, no, it's just getting late....
아니 그보다 이제 시간도 늦고 해서..
아냐, 괜찮아.
아직 마가리타도 충분히 남았으니까.
Hey, hey, hey. That's fine. It's totally fine.
We have plenty of margaritas. It's all good.
I don't even know what that's for.
저건 또 뭐지?
저기 말야. 나 아무래도
남아야 할 거 같아. 걱정 되서.
You know what?
I think I'm gonna stay here and make sure he's okay.
그래 그게 좋을 것 같아.
Yeah. That's probably a good idea.
Yeah, just I'll see you in the morning.
아침에 보자고.
Ah-ha. Okay.
응. 알았어. 근데 있지,
Yeah, you know, Joey. I , I don't think he's ever gonna be okay with this.
조이. 아마도 평생 가도
괜찮아질 것 같지 않아보여.
Well, doesn't look good, does it?
그래보이지?
Morning!
일어났냐? 마셔.
Here you go. / Thanks
고마워. 밤새 여기 있었어?
Did you, you stay here all night?
Yeah.
응.
So you took off my pants and shoes?
그럼 니가 내 바지랑 신발 벗긴 거야?
아니 '시카고' 사운드트랙 들으면서
알아서 벗던데?
No, no, no. You actually did that when you were dancing to the "Chicago" soundtrack.
Look, uh, Ross, about Rachel and I ,
저기, 나랑 레이첼 있잖아..
걱정하지마. 아무 일 없을 테니까.
Listen, you don't have to worry about that, okay, because nothing's gonna happen.
What do you mean?
무슨 말이야?
Well, she and I said from the beginning that we weren't gonna do anything unless you're okay with it.
우리 둘이 처음부터 약속했던 거야.
만약 니가 안 괜찮으면 없었던 일로 하기로.
And clearly...
Hey, what are you talking about? I'm fine!
무슨 말이야, 나 멀쩡하대두~
It's okay, Ross. You know? I, I totally understand.
괜찮아. 이해한다고.
Of course you're not fine. You're ....
너희 둘이잖아. 로스와 레이첼.
You're Ross and Rachel.
Yeah, except we're not.
그래 하지만 우린 헤어진지 6년이 넘었어.
I mean we haven't been a couple in like ....
six years?
Oh my God! Is that right?
말도 안돼, 그렇게 오래 됐나?
Has it been that long?
정말 그렇게 오래 된거야?
내가 듣기론.
That's what I hear, yeah.
Ha, this is crazy. I mean six years
이건 말도 안돼. 6년?
그런데 나 때문에 너희 둘이 안 사귄다고?
and because of me you guys aren't gonna be together?
뭐 하나 물어봐도 돼?
Can I ask you something?
Really,
너랑 레이첼.. 어떤 감정이야?
What is this thing with you and Rachel?
Come on, you know me. You know.
나 어떤지 알잖아.
조이.
Joey.
I'm crazy about her.
좋아 죽겠어.
And she feels the same way?
레이첼도 마찬가지고?
I think so.
아마도.
Well then, maybe it's time we all moved on.
그렇다면.. 이제 우리
서로에게서 벗어날 때가 된 거 같네.
Yeah, but Ross, I mean, you're not okay with it.
하지만 니가 안 괜찮잖아.
아냐.. 괜찮고 싶어.
No, but...
I want to be.
그리고.. 괜찮아질 거야.
Hey,... I will be.
난 이제 찰리랑 사귀잖아..
Besides, I'm, I'm with Charlie, right?
Oh my God! I'm still with Charlie, aren't I?
잠깐, 아직 사귀는 거 맞지?
나 춤추는 거 못 봤지?
I mean she didn't see the dance, did she?
No, no, no.
아냐, 그건 나만 봤지.
That was ,uh , ...
That was just for me.
Are you, uh,...
너.. 정말 괜찮은 거야?
Are you sure about this?
Yeah. I'm sure.
응.
And we're okay? /Huh.
우리는?
번 역 ㅣ 단형철 ㅣ divine0422@freechal.com
싱 크 ㅣ 변정주 ㅣ jungjoo@kaist.ac.kr
테스트 ㅣ 오종현 ㅣ hiro97@hanmir.com
Hey Pheebs, / Hey.
피비 미리 말해줄 게 있는데..
빌하고 콜린 우리 싫어해.
We just want to give you a heads-up.
Bill and Coleen hate us.
Owen didn't know he was adopted
오웬은 입양에 대해 모르고있었는데
모니카가 말해버렸어.
Monica told him. / What?
Still he had to find out some time.
그래도 오웬도 언젠간 알았어야 할 일이니까.
Yeah, but how would you like it if someone told the triplets you gave birth to them?
그건 그렇지만 만약에 누가 세쌍둥이한테
니가 걔들 생모라고 말하면 어떻겠어?
I'm gonna go tell Emma she was an accident.
난 에마한테 걔가
실수로 태어난거라고 말해주러 갈게.